Herb Yellin Papers Relating to Joyce Carol Oates
Herb Yellin Papers Relating to Joyce Carol Oates
1976-2000
Yellin, Herb.
0.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, memorabilia and printed material relating to Yellin's Lord John Press and to author Joyce Carol Oates, several of whose short works were printed by Yellin
4586337
Biographical History
Herb Yellin (1935-2014) was an American book collector and publisher. He founded Lord John Press in 1976 to publish signed limited editions of significant American authors. Joyce Carol Oates (1938- ) is a an award-winning American author of fiction and non-fiction, including novels, short stories, poems, plays, and essays.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Herb Yellin Papers Relating to Joyce Carol Oates consists of correspondence, memorabilia and printed material relating to Yellin's Lord John Press and to author Joyce Carol Oates, several of whose short works were published by Yellin. The collection two folders of detailed and friendly personal correspondence between Yellin and Oates.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type or topic.
Related Material
See also the
Joyce Carol Oates Papers
. also has a large number of books, articles, serials and other items by or pertaining to Oates which are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection. Please search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Women Authors; Ewert, William B.; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-; Yellin, Herb.; Lord John Press.; Novelists, American -- 20th century.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Private presses -- California.; Women authors -- 20th century.; Women poets, American.; Broadsides (notices); Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Publishers and publishing.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
A few financial items are not accessible to researchers at this time. These items are stored separately in internal files.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 2015.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Boyers, Robert (Bennington College), 1979 (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Blanche, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1976-2000; undated; detailed and friendly correspondence, including typescripts of several poems by Oates; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - re: Petrie family, typed page plus several hand-drawn family trees [?] regarding the Petrie family, by unknown author (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978; 1993; includes notes to printers about various Oates projects, letter regarding an Oates biography, etc. (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Financial material, cancelled checks from Yellin to Oates and Oates to Yellin
    This material is not available to researchers at this time.
  - Joyce Carol Oates Newsletter, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated; candid color photographs of Oates with Yellin, apparently at a book signing (Box 1)
- Printed material by Oates
  - Articles, 1987; 1996; reprints, signed and inscribed to Yellin (Box 1)
  - Broadsides, undated; limited edition small-press printed items by Oates; includes Lord John Press, Tamarack Press, others (Oversize 1)
  - Broadsides and cards, undated; limited edition small-press printed items by Oates; includes Lord John Press, Tamarack Press, others; several are signed by Oates (Box 1)
  - Galleys
    - Fertilizing the Continent, Santa Susanna press, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Luxury of Sin, Lord John Press, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Queen of the Night, Lord John Press, 1979 (Box 1)
    - The Stepfather, Lord John Press, 1978 (Box 1)
    - The Time Traveler, Lord John Press, 1987 (Box 1)
    - White Trash, Lord John Press, undated (Box 1)